<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenEMR</title>
    <link>https://www.openemr.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on OpenEMR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>OEMR</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openemr.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenEMR, A Great Long Term Choice</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/great-long-term-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/great-long-term-choice/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a free and open source EMR with a history of success around the world is a great move for those looking to avoid vendor lock-in. As a mature project with a vibrant community, OpenEMR is a great choice for the long term because the provider owns both the data and the software, and cannot be charged for it &amp;ndash; ever!
Our group has recently noticed an uptick in cost-sensitive clinicians moving from a previously freeware EMR that introduced a new pricing model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenEMR Medical Image Viewer</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/medical-image-viewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/medical-image-viewer/</guid>
      <description>A team of software engineers within our community recently built the first major medical imaging feature into the system. Given a DICOM file in a patient chart, users can now utilize an easy-to-use medical image visualizer.
By using a capable open-source, web-based DICOM image viewer, OpenEMR provides clinicians a quick, secure, and robust view into patient images with windowing, panning, zooming, and filtering support. The underlying technology is based on the DICOM Web Viewer (DWV) open-source project led by Yves Martelli, a software engineer and medical imaging expert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepting Donations on OpenCollective</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/accepting-donations-on-opencollective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/accepting-donations-on-opencollective/</guid>
      <description>Donate on OpenCollective
As the most popular open source electronic health records and medical practice management solution, our community has many ambitious goals to meet the needs of our global user base. Some of these requests involve activities such as adding new clinical forms, improving documentation, and crafting a cutting edge, FHIR-ready, real-time inpatient management module. I’ll let you guess which one requires the most energy, time, and domain expertise :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Maria, Puerto Rico, and the success of OpenEMR customers</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/hurricane-maria-puerto-rico-openemr-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/hurricane-maria-puerto-rico-openemr-success/</guid>
      <description>Throughout both Hurricane Maria’s initial impact and the rebuilding efforts, Puerto Rico has suffered tremendous infrastructure damage leaving the majority of the islands some 3.4 million people without power, water, communications, and internet access. Despite these challenges, OpenEMR would prove to be vital at multiple healthcare facilities as the island begins the process of rebuilding.
During and immediately following the hurricane’s devastating wind and rain, the following healthcare providers noted OpenEMR as an essential tool in receiving and assisting a large volume of patients:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenEMR and the 2017 VCU HealthHacks</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/healthhacks-at-vcu-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/healthhacks-at-vcu-2017/</guid>
      <description>OpenEMR is proud to be a contributing sponsor of the 2017 HealthHacks at VCU a 24-hour event at Virginia Commonwealth University involving engineering, medical, and computer science students coming together to problem solve and innovate on current unmet medical needs.
&amp;ldquo;HealthHacks is a rapid-paced participatory event for students of all disciplines to engage with medical professionals in development and prototyping of solutions for unmet needs in patientcare. It is a very exciting 24-hour engagement event,&amp;rdquo; said L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenEMR Announces Initial Availability of OpenEMR Cloud on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/openemr-announces-initial-availability-of-openemr-cloud-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/openemr-announces-initial-availability-of-openemr-cloud-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>Setup Guide CloudFormation Template
OpenEMR Cloud Full Stack, a cloud service version of OpenEMR - the most popular open source electronic health record (EHR) and medical practice management solution, is available for the 5.0.0.5 release of OpenEMR. OpenEMR has joined with industry leading Amazon Web Services (AWS) to implement and deliver OpenEMR Cloud to healthcare provider practices and institutions throughout the world. In a few simple steps, healthcare providers can leverage the benefits of OpenEMR and AWS by deploying OpenEMR Cloud Full Stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Blog Administrator
Aenean ipsum justo, semper eu nisl ut, pretium tincidunt sem. Praesent et diam sit amet lacus lobortis dictum a id lacus. Quisque hendrerit sit amet turpis eu varius. Ut id lorem ac felis ultrices tincidunt. Pellentesque consequat arcu ac fringilla imperdiet. Phasellus pellentesque, sapien non pulvinar blandit, sapien ante aliquet felis, vel porttitor sapien ante in lacus. Fusce non urna aliquet, malesuada nibh vel, luctus urna. Phasellus ut lacus molestie, varius purus quis, malesuada lorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/page/about/</guid>
      <description>OpenEMR is the most popular open source electronic health records and medical practice management solution. ONC certified with international usage, OpenEMR&amp;rsquo;s goal is a superior alternative to its proprietary counterparts. With passionate volunteers and contributors dedicated to guarding OpenEMR&amp;rsquo;s status as a free, open source software solution for medical practices with a commitment to openness, kindness and cooperation.
To stay connected, subscribe to the RSS feed of this blog posts, or follow us on Twitter @openemr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>