<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on OpenEMR</title>
    <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on OpenEMR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>OEMR</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openemr.blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepting Donations on OpenCollective</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/accepting-donations-on-opencollective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/accepting-donations-on-opencollective/</guid>
      <description>Donate on OpenCollective
As the most popular open source electronic health records and medical practice management solution, our community has many ambitious goals to meet the needs of our global user base. Some of these requests involve activities such as adding new clinical forms, improving documentation, and crafting a cutting edge, FHIR-ready, real-time inpatient management module. I’ll let you guess which one requires the most energy, time, and domain expertise :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Maria, Puerto Rico, and the success of OpenEMR customers</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/hurricane-maria-puerto-rico-openemr-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/hurricane-maria-puerto-rico-openemr-success/</guid>
      <description>Throughout both Hurricane Maria’s initial impact and the rebuilding efforts, Puerto Rico has suffered tremendous infrastructure damage leaving the majority of the islands some 3.4 million people without power, water, communications, and internet access. Despite these challenges, OpenEMR would prove to be vital at multiple healthcare facilities as the island begins the process of rebuilding.
During and immediately following the hurricane’s devastating wind and rain, the following healthcare providers noted OpenEMR as an essential tool in receiving and assisting a large volume of patients:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenEMR and the 2017 VCU HealthHacks</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/healthhacks-at-vcu-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/healthhacks-at-vcu-2017/</guid>
      <description>OpenEMR is proud to be a contributing sponsor of the 2017 HealthHacks at VCU a 24-hour event at Virginia Commonwealth University involving engineering, medical, and computer science students coming together to problem solve and innovate on current unmet medical needs.
&amp;ldquo;HealthHacks is a rapid-paced participatory event for students of all disciplines to engage with medical professionals in development and prototyping of solutions for unmet needs in patientcare. It is a very exciting 24-hour engagement event,&amp;rdquo; said L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenEMR Announces Initial Availability of OpenEMR Cloud on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.openemr.blog/post/openemr-announces-initial-availability-of-openemr-cloud-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openemr.blog/post/openemr-announces-initial-availability-of-openemr-cloud-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>Setup Guide CloudFormation Template
OpenEMR Cloud Full Stack, a cloud service version of OpenEMR - the most popular open source electronic health record (EHR) and medical practice management solution, is available for the 5.0.0.5 release of OpenEMR. OpenEMR has joined with industry leading Amazon Web Services (AWS) to implement and deliver OpenEMR Cloud to healthcare provider practices and institutions throughout the world. In a few simple steps, healthcare providers can leverage the benefits of OpenEMR and AWS by deploying OpenEMR Cloud Full Stack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>